Email: kiran\_bisht22@yahoo.com kineadi@gmail.com

#### Brief Overview: -

~15.10 yrs. experience in the field of HR with an exposure towards the entire gamut of HR involving Talent Acquisition, Induction, Verification, Employees Relation, Performance Appraisal, HR operations, MIS Reports, Training and Development, Employee engagement and separation.

#### Work Experience: -



📥 Last / Current Employer: - Bioture Labs Pvt. Ltd.

Designation - Senior Manager - Human Resource & BD (Hybrid mode) Duration - 1st June 2016 till 31st March 2020 Assignments handled -

- Headhunt and manage recruitments through various channels and fulfil requirements in consultation with the centre Head as well as with Group HR head for Key Positions.
- To periodically visit and administer the technical centre unit at Gandhinagar and ensure that all staff records (leave, Attendance, OD etc) and data are periodically updated and in line with the required protocol.
- Implement Corporate HR policies and monitor strict adherence and keep check on Statutory compliances. Managed entry to exit cycle of employees which includes Orientation, Training, engagement, grievances and separation.
- To continuously survey the internet and other literatures to identify possible business opportunity for the company. To work closely with the Technical centre Head in sending promotional mails to concerned Pharmaceuticals and allied companies.
- To help in preparation and organisation of technical documents for the clients to the centre Head.
- 📥 Previous Employer: Advanced Hair Studio Pvt. Ltd. **Designation - HR Manager**

Duration - 31st Aug 2015 till 7th May 2016 KRAs: -

- Streamlining & implementation of policies, Maintaining and fulfilling Statutory requirements.
- Manpower planning and budgeting, Recruitment Pan India, Vendor Management.
- Training, PMS.
- Leave attendance, Involved in compensation and benefits,
- Employee engagement activities Fun at work, Grievance handling, Separation Management.
- Conduct reward and recognition program.

# 📥 Previous Employer: Panoramic Group of Companies, Mumbai

Assignments handled - was actively involved in the expansion of Timeshare division -Magic Holidays with its presence spread across at 14 branches Pan India along with the Travel division- Panoramic Tours & Travels Ltd., PCL, PCL holidays, Buzz4hotels.

Designation: - Senior Manager Human Resources - Pan India Duration: - 7<sup>th</sup> May 12 till 30<sup>th</sup> June 15. KRAs: -

- ♣ Implementation of the policies and define procedures from time to time as per requirement – Recruitment cycle, On-boarding, Confirmations, Transfer, PIP, Rehiring, database to manage entry till exit.
- Leading the Talent Acquisition & HR Operations team of about 17 team members Instrumental in setting up Mumbai, Pune & Rest of Maharashtra, eventually to Lead and open of the upcoming branches PAN India through several sources.
- Working out Salary fitments, Rolling-out offers, Joining formalities & On-boarding process.
- Vendor Management.
- Talent Management PMS Pan India.
- Managing Employees Relation, Employee engagement.
- Organization & employee development.

Previous Employer: - Cox & Kings India Ltd., Head Office Mumbai

Designation: - HR Manager

Duration: - 1st Mar 07 till 4th Jan 12.

KRAs: -

- Leading the Talent Acquisition Team Pan India, involved partly in international hiring
  - a) Responsible for managing entire recruitments life cycle and Talent acquisition across PAN India
  - b) Facilitate compensation negotiations, final offers & joining
  - c) Responsible for following pre-defined norms for resourcing cycle time, placement cost, selection ratio, joining ratio etc.
  - d) Proactive candidate development specifically in the senior management level
  - e) Responsible for carrying back-end operations like preparing job descriptions, interview schedules, compensations details, offer letters, for Vendor management.
  - f) Handling Joining formalities followed by induction program
  - g) Worked on Quality calibration project for new Joiners.
- Formulating, Streamlining and Implementation of HR policies such as Leave, Attendance, Travel, Referral etc.,
- Talent Management PMS Pan India.
  - a) Coordinating the formulation & implementation of increment, incentive & other remuneration policies.
  - b) Overseeing the Performance Management System across the levels and establishing framework for substantiating the Appraisal process linked to Rewards Management.
- ♣ Training & Development.
  - a) Preparing Training Identification needs based on the Appraisal exercise Basis which organize Training programs & involved in Coordinating for the same.
- **♣** Employees Relation, Employee engagement.
  - a) Finalization and implementation of the yearly Engagement calendar.
  - b) Designing and implementing effective reward and recognition procedures in line with the business strategy.
  - c) Designing and implementing E-SAT and other employee motivation measurement tools.
  - d) Organize Outdoor activities in line with the vibrant culture of the organization e.g., Fun Fridays, Festival celebrations.
- ♣ Organization & employee development
  - a) Designed New Job Description template for all exiting roles, job titling exercise and revised designations based on the function
  - b) Designed and implemented an Employee Satisfaction Survey to measure the employee engagement and commitment.

## Previous Employer: - I-Link Infosoft (G) Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad

**Designation: - HR Manager** 

Duration: - 26th Dec 05 to 30th January 2007

#### KRAs: -

- Preparing & Implementing Policies.
- Recruitment, Selection, Induction.
- ♣ Handling Entry to Exit Cycle.
- Training & Development.
- ♣ Preparing Intent letter, Appointment, Termination & Relieving letters.
- ♣ Co-ordination with Departmental Heads.
- Drafting Memos.
- Performance Appraisals.
- Retention.
- Increments.
- Attendance and Leaves.
- Executing Bonus plans for the employees.
- Employees Relation.

## Previous Employer: - Belltek Technologies, Mumbai

#### **Designation: - Senior HR Executive**

Duration: - 21<sup>st</sup> June 2004 till 30<sup>th</sup> September 2004 (On 3months contract) KRAs: -

- Preparing Policies, Procedures & streamlining the same.
- Recruitment, Induction.
- ♣ Employees Relation, Attendance & leave.
- Training & Development Coordinating and identifying training needs.
- Retention, Incentive Scheme.
- Exit Interview.
- ♣ Employees Welfare Suggestion Scheme, Employee Referrals Scheme.
- Handling responsibilities of consultancy.

## A Previous Employer: - Jupiter e-Services Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon

#### **Designation: - Senior HR Executive**

### Duration: - 18<sup>th</sup> March 2004 till 18<sup>th</sup> Jun 2004

#### KRAs: -

- Manpower Planning & Budgeting
- Recruitment
- ♣ Induction & Training
- Retention
- Exit Interview
- ♣ Employees Welfare Suggestion Scheme, Employee Referrals Scheme, Attendance
- Incentive Scheme.
- Handling Employees Grievances.
- Attendance & leave
- Preparing Policies, Procedures & streamlining the same.

### A Previous Employer: - Miaect Pvt. Ltd., Vashi Navi Mumbai.

### **Designation: - HR Executive**

## Duration: - 15<sup>th</sup> May 2003 to 16<sup>th</sup> March 2004

#### KRAs: -

- Recruitment
- Induction & Training
- Employees Relation & certain other issues.
- ♣ Drafting Memos, Appointment Letters, Circulars.
- Coordination with various branches
- Attendance & Leave monitoring.
- Salaries Reports
- Monitoring Monthly Reports
- Coordinating & conducting Performance Appraisal
- Was involved in Preparing Policies & Procedures of the company.



## Previous Employer: - Vonarise Management

**Designation: - Management Trainee Duration:** - 1<sup>st</sup> May 2002 to 14<sup>th</sup> May 2003

KRAs: -

- Involved in assisting areas of Recruitment, Training, Suggestion Scheme
- Co-ordination with various Departments, Attendance etc.

### Professional Qualification: -

- Completed Masters Management Studies (MMS) from Pillai's Institute of Management Studies and Research Panvel, Mumbai University in 2002
- Passed BSc (Microbiology) from Modern College Vashi, Mumbai University in 2000.

### Technical Qualification: -

- 1. Diploma in Information Technology MS Office
- 2. Operating Systems Ms Access, Unix, Dos
- 3. Languages C++.

#### Personal Details: -

Name : Kiran S Negi : 9920485705. Contact no.

Current Address: A-801, Sharan Sapphire, Koteshwar Bhat road, Motera, Ahmedabad.

: Confident, Quick Learner, Patience, Team player. Strengths

Marital Status : Married : 22<sup>nd</sup>April 1980 Date of Birth

### References: -

1. Ms. Brinda Purohit Karnik

AVP - HR TimesPro. Mumbai. M-9821639009 2. Mr. Nitin Ambulkar National Manager -HR & IR LINFOX LOGISTICS (INDIA) PRIVATE LIMITED, Mumbai. M-9870107000

Date:-Sign:-